hello it's March 22nd 2023
we're in
cohort 2
in our second discussion of chapter nine
we're gonna Jump Right In
to anything that people are thinking
about
related to chapter nine or
just in general so whoever would like to
bring something up go for it
yeah
uh so I have a question that you you
said last last time I don't know whether
it was in what context it exactly was
that you would you would say we talked
about or you talked about
um about affordances and you said that
policies are not affordances
and then I was wondering what then
affordances are because I understood
policies are not affordances because
they are in the future
but but then
I was thinking what that should mean
because the present is a point in time
infinitely small
so which would imply that affordances
doesn't exist
or how would you see this
so if one thinks that an affordance is
yeah if we are in this in one state
and the policy is a sequence of states
in the future
but then even if we have this embedded
States I can be in the state of learning
for instance active inference
which also
I mean implies some actions in the
future so I was a little bit confused
about this notion and why you would
think that policies are not references
maybe I misunderstood
thanks Ali money of a first thought and
then I'll be happy to add some
okay well uh yeah actually
uh well in fact in active inference
literature there are some Divergence
between the way terms uh used uh in this
context uh as as compared to uh their
other connotations or other meanings in
some other contexts such as
reinforcement learning and so on so uh
basically uh in active inference by
policy uh they generally mean a sequence
of actions
uh but for instance in RL learning
policy is defined as just a single
action and affordance again is a kind of
problematic term because we have
different Notions of accordance for
example in uh
ecological psychology or in some other
areas but uh to the best of my
understanding in active inference
um affordance refers simply to a single
action in some cases
but in some other cases it can take on
some other additional layers of mean
so for example weaken ordinances or
pragmatic affordances and
they they somehow uh conflated with each
other and uh they they can be confusing
to uh delineate which uh notion of
affordance is referred to here in this
context so yeah those are pretty much
the basic uh or at least some of the
points that can help
to delineate those two concepts
accordance and uh
policy but I'm sure Daniel would have
some other thoughts on that as well
awesome yes
a lot of good points so big picture
there are divergences between how the
terms are used in active and in
reinforcement ecological psychology
we hope and basically believe that
there's coherence in how the terms are
used but that doesn't guarantee
coherence within and across areas which
themselves are not necessarily
internally or externally consistent so
policies are sequences of actions over a
given time Horizon
affordances are the instantaneous single
action possibilities described by the E
variable so map not territory if you're
in a maze and you can be going up down
left right then those are your
affordances and over a Time Horizon of
four you can have policies of a Time
Horizon of four with all the
combinatorial possibilities
of up down left right
to the fourth power
um
then there are there are those sometimes
informally applied statements like a
pragmatic affordance or an epistemic
affordance
which is like when action is being taken
that is
oriented around epistemic value but this
is not like a this is kind of like a
modifier
like it's a risky affordance or it's a
um you know
fun affordance
not necessarily like a special subtype
in a formal way
um
and it's described by the E variable you
could have a nested generative model so
like live stream 42 with a slam
simultaneous localization and mapping at
the lower level the robot has up down
left right affordances
at the higher level
the policy selection the affordances
have to do with locations moving amongst
locations
and so
you can have nested affordances because
you can have nested models that's not
any controversial or hot take on the
system itself
it's just describing the model and then
um what we can look into more and what
Paulo is researching uh and and some
others is explicitly in contrast with
the ecological psychology concept of the
gibsonian affordance
use
what was also called like affordance 1.0
2.0 and then Maxwell ramstead taking the
perspective that active inference
affordances are affordance is 3.0
The gibsonian Advocates
emphasize that affordances are directly
perceived action capacities
so for them indeed it is not making
sense that there could be affordances in
the future but people have also
considered planning from an ecological
psychology perspective
but their emphasis is on the direct
perception
of action possibilities
which coming from the e Vector
perspective it's kind of like take it or
leave it
the E Vector might be
known
in a metacognitive way might be directly
perceived
or it might not
sorry what is an e vector
the E Vector is with the capacities for
action
here and step by step
the E Vector is the habit
these are the actions that can be taken
are enumerated
and the values in the cells reflect the
prior on action
we can see that in the textbook
in
[Music]
um
the figures for chapter five
so
here
we have a dopamine
mediated so neuromodulator mediated
uh balance
between two modes of policy selection
here in some dopaminergic regions in the
mammalian brain
so in both cases observations are coming
in
in the indirect pathway
the E Vector is basically passed along
and the policy posterior
which could be sampled from neutrally
or you can have a shaky hand and erase
differences in the policy posterior
or you could have a precise hand and
always select the maximum element
maximum posterior action probability
in the indirect pathway
The Habit Vector is basically just
passed along
so action selection resembles action
prior
whereas in the
expected free energy deliberative type 2
archetype of action selection
there's this
sharpening or updating
of the action prior
into a policy posterior that's been
re-weighted by expected free energy
This is highly schematic and like not
all the variables are shown
in many cases
it's just schema
so habits is something bottom up sorry
and um
and the g Vector is something top down
so that's plant and the other one is
hmm
routine or something
yeah yes
um yes
um
yes
as always these are aspects of
generative models not of organisms
so it's hard because we want to be
referring to the habits and the
deliberation patterns
that cognitive systems do
but also be aware that like e and G are
phenomena of our model they're not
phenomenas of the world but that being
said the role of E
is to
through its membership or composition
enumerate what instantaneous actions are
possible
if there's up down left right then the E
Vector is going to have four elements
if there's nine directions it can move
then e has a length of nine
the values within the E vector
are the prior on those actions being
selected in an instance
so if there was a uniform e Vector
across up down left right one one one
one
then there's no prior
asymmetry
towards taking any of those
um
actions
whereas if the E Vector was 10 1 1 1
then that is equivalent to saying like
that
um
in the absence of further expected free
energy updates
that action prior will be recapitulated
in future action and so you can imagine
a model where e is updatable or not
like a simple updating model for e
would be every time you take an action
drop a pebble into that urn
so that's the learning as counting
strategy
which works for for many things
so that
the
um action
prior
comes to embody previous action
posteriors that's habit
and so what initially may have required
a deliberative expected free energy
expenditure
becomes canalized or entrenched
in e
allowing for example skill
or skillful performance
to occur
without
the um deliberative
High dopamine
setting
in figure 5.4
here the dopamine variables gamma
and um
yes two of the places to look for
further discussion on that some of it is
um the ontology
project where with Paolo and others
we're talking about like
um ramstead and Camaro and all of these
different perspectives on affordance and
representation
and also there's been an interesting
discussion about like similarities and
differences with A continuous in the
discrete time model so the affordance is
3.0 discussion and then the other angle
for critical perspectives on the octave
strategies and counter rebuttals is the
Markov blanket trick
Ollie
I just wanted to point to a kind of
possible point of conf
a point of possible confusion that can
arise uh when dealing with these ABC
sorry d e matrices and vectors uh
because uh it's sometimes it's difficult
to remember which Matrix or which Vector
encodes what so one simple mnemonic that
I found helpful in Remembering those
notation notational conventions is as we
go from a to e we move from
instantaneous observations uh into our
prior and learned and habit
um beliefs about the world so for
instance a encodes our beliefs about the
relationship between the hidden States
and the observable outcomes B is about
the likelihood of the transition C
encodes our preferences the encodes our
beliefs about initial hidden States and
finally e encodes our habits uh so yeah
I think that might help to remember
those terms
awesome and and G some kind of
metaphysical
expectations or something like this or
what is cheating
um so well it's all metaphysical they're
all informational because they're all
variables
although one can take the Chris Fields
perspective information as physics
yeah yeah yeah but that being said
um we continue down the line with f as a
variational free energy
and
um G as expected free energy
um however these are all
symbols
and uh there's sort of a a common
set of symbols in some sense but but
they're they're by no means necessarily
these letters I kind of goes without
saying but it definitely can be a point
of confusion but
um let's look at
our favorite step by step
pull in the image for the 100th time
foreign
oh
observation
s
hidden state
d
prior on hidden States
a the emission recognition Matrix
between s and O this is the tale of two
densities
because a can go from s to O
emitting in the generative Direction
plausible observations from hidden
States or a can be used in its
recognition capacity to update s based
upon incoming observations
so
in the upper left static perception case
all you need to appeal to is a b or I'm
sorry A and D
S and L
then Dynamic perception it's still
passive
but it's changing through time and what
changes the hidden State through time is
B the transition Matrix on hidden States
to enable policy selection
at least two other things have to come
into play
well at least one but really two the one
that must come into play is simply the
enumeration of action capacities which
is
listed
in the membership of E
and the cells contain quantitative
information on the prior probability of
those actions being selected AKA habit
you could have
e and just be taking actions
however what is it that steers the ship
on which actions are selected
well
the way we do that in active inference
is not by proposing a utility function
and maximizing utility function in a
reward function
but
to encode through C
our preferences
what we expect slash prefer
we talk about them as preferences
because they play a functional role
teleologically as preferences in the
sense that pragmatic Behavior reduces
the Divergence between observations and
preferences
so in the sense that their preferences
they are that
but what C does
is it's like a thumb on the scale of
observations
not by changing anything downstairs with
the Tail of Two densities
but rather
through expected free energy
selecting policies
that are expected to reduce the
Divergence between observations and
expectations
and by way of reducing divergences
between observations and expectations
about observations
we acquire pragmatic value
oriented towards C
in the extreme case fully realizing C
exactly having a homeostatic temperature
exactly having how much money we want in
the bank whatever it is
and so functionally C is called
preferences
and then there's this little extra piece
on the right
that's also reflected in that
dopaminergic image
with gamma
as a temperature gamma and beta is one
over each other
and those gamma being a parameterization
of a big gamma distribution
and then be one over each other so
whether you choose to think about it as
like temperature or inverse temperature
that is a Precision on policy selection
and then last thought on this
this is not the only active inference
model
you could have a Precision on anything
you can have a Precision on D you could
have a Precision on a
you could have a Precision on B
so these are like some birds I've seen
this is not the overall exhaustive zoo
of all possible birds or the one
possible bird
these are like certain configurations of
Base graphs
which we can use a controlled ontology
to describe
so that we can apply them in cybernetic
contexts for example designing
ecosystems of shared intelligence
Ollie
I also believe beta is technically
called stochasticity so in some
literature they explicitly use this term
stochasticity to refer to that
beta parameter which sometimes uh for
the sake of Simplicity is equated to one
in order to not
complicate the distributions especially
the gaussian distribution so
um but sometimes they can be just it can
be arbitrary value of a stochasticity
yes thank you
um and when we see the um the learning
figure 710
here
learning in a Bayesian setting
can be seen as as having a prior on that
variable
so if we have a fixed parameter
d
then it's just like a um
like a Dirac Delta
#category Theory
but it's like one point that's just
fixed
and it's a fixed value
there's two states and it's one zero so
just it is the first day
or
you could imagine
the instantiation of that prior
parameterization
to be drawn from another distribution
and then you could imagine learning or
updating within that setting
but if you have just a fixed parameter
then it it can't be updated
but if you have a fixed parameter or
associated with a prior
then you've opened the door to learning
and invoked all of these other
kind of Bayesian considerations like
making sure that your prior is not
simply being recapitulated in the output
so like testing for different priors and
doing all these different things
for standards rigorous Bayesian
statistics Michael
yeah so in this graph that you just
showed the
um an affordance would then be the
relation between s and O
um no it doesn't know hidden States and
observations
so a is the tale of two densities here's
the temperature of the room s and the
thermometer o
so the recognition density is what's the
temperature
given the reading and then the
generative density direction is from the
temperature what's the thermometer
so the downstairs
is all passive inference
downstairs passive inference here's our
prior on the temperature in the room
temperature in the room changing through
time we're not doing anything about it
and at every time step it's emitting an
observation
where action comes in is in the upstairs
with E the actions that we can take
and Associated habituality around them
and then as to do more than simply
recapitulate habit
we have preferences
which have a semantics of being
expectations about observations
I expect myself to be homeostatic and
I'm going to take actions that make that
realized
so reward learning paradigm
I'm rewarded by having homeostatic
temperature and I follow policies that
are rewarding
active inference self-evidencing
paradigm
I expect to be homeostatic
and so I take action selection
to reduce divergences between the
observations that I do get and what I
expect slash prefer
so so how does the can the notion of
affordances then be explained with these
graphs that you showed is it a vertical
slide
through this this architecture or I mean
it has to do with uh with the o
and with preferences that's what you
just said right
the actions are taken uh I mean in a way
the actions are taken in the Adaptive
case
in service
pragmatically
of reducing the Divergence between C and
O
that is pragmatic value is reducing that
and that's where the KL Divergence we're
reducing the Divergence between C and O
that's pragmatic value epistemic value
is
reducing our uncertainty about different
things
where the affordances can it be seen as
like a slice in time in this graph so
the affordances are enumerated in the E
variable
and in every single time step they are
going to be crunched by G
and then B
let's just say that there are two
affordances we can turn the heater on or
we can have the heater off so B
is going to have
um two slices
B is like a tensor
it can be any the dimensionality is
really important and looking at the
notebooks and the code around these
things is some of the best way to get
intuition for this but basically B has a
slice
for every affordance
so there's like a b like a transition
Matrix for the heater being off
and then there's a transition Matrix for
the heater being on
so like let's just say that in our
hidden State there's three temperatures
um cold medium and hot
so again map not territory we're not
saying that there isn't a quantitative
temperature in the room it's just we're
choosing to model the hidden state with
three discrete States
and so if the heater is off the B Matrix
let's just say looks like the identity
Matrix
so if the heater is off
the room's temperature does not change
if the heater is on
we bump from cold to medium medium to
hot and we stay in hot
and so then the ones would be like in
different locations on that slice of B
what do you think about that
yeah so trying to digest so so
you're saying the affordances are occur
encoded in the transitions between
states
um the affordances are most plainly
listed in the E variable
however
every affordance
is also represented
with a different transitions different
transitions slice in the world
if there was just one transition Matrix
then our action wouldn't do anything
because the world is just going to
change the way it's going to change no
matter what we select
so then all policies would be equally
meaningless
in service of reducing the Divergence
between our preferences and observations
so again not a feature of the real world
that there's actually a b Matrix out
there that has a number of slices
equivalents the number of actions that
can be taken
but given the dimensionality of E
there is a slice corresponding to each
element of e in b
and then if affordance one is taken
slice 1
is used in the transition
if affordance 2 is taken
slice 2 is used in passing s forward
okay and what um
what if there is somehow
an implication if I'm in right now and
there's an implication for the future
and well perhaps not really a a
deterministic one but um
so I decide with my
decision right now it's what happens in
the future but the future would not be
an affordance in that sense even though
it's part of maybe a policy it's not an
affordance because it's not
related to to that transition
that is immediately
activated that's right now the case
something like this
that that's a a a
commendable
compatibilist position between the
ecological psychologist and active
inference
is like saying well affordances are real
in the moment
and so policies which also include
actions that are taken potentially in
the future like imagined actions
those are also those will be real in
their moment
and they're cognitively real in this
moment
and that's why this also invokes the
discussion around representationalism
because if one takes a realist
perspective and says well this is what
they're doing
they're evaluating all counterfactuals
in the organism's brain
or in the computer program or something
versus is this just an instrumental
analytical framework
that doesn't actually mean
that there's an e vector or the
enumeration of counterfactual policies
at all
so the realist angle would be this is
the causal architecture
and it's and patterns in this base graph
will be associated with for example
neural activity patterns
which can be understood as neural
representations of these quantities and
processes
the instrumentalist is under absolutely
no
compulsion
for this architecture
to reflect anything in specific about
the slime mold the ant colony the
civilization
it's not like there actually has to be
the enumeration of counterfactuals
about hypothetical action sequences
but we list those as a convenience
and then we can apply tree surge
branching time active inference etc etc
as heuristics
in the space that is combinatorially
constructed
but that from an instrumentalist point
of view
doesn't mean that's what the system is
doing
and that is like at one of one of the
heart of the tension
because the gibsonian affordance concept
centers
a quintessentially realist phenomena
which is what the organism is actually
instantaneously perceiving in terms of
action capacities
chairs are for sitting
which means
potentially under like some people's
interpretation of radical inactivism
like if you don't see the chair
you're not having that instantaneous
perception of action capacity
whereas an act of inference especially
from an instrumental reading
were basically
on the plus side
completely free from that
but on the downside
people need to be very careful that they
don't sneak the realism back in
and say well here's going to be the
central nervous system just conceptually
decision making and here's going to be
the nested model of the hand
and then it's all good they go off on
their instrumental way and then all of a
sudden they're interpreting this is the
elbow
as if this architecture was reflecting
for example something anatomical
so instrumentalism allows one to fly
freely with this analytical framework
and leave a lot of baggage at the door
however in the case where realist
conclusions are being sought
to be constructed
one has to be careful that they weren't
actually taking a covert realism along
for the ride
the good news is I think people can do
that
because they don't have any problems
with linear regression
but then again some do in some cases
but the architecture of that base graph
can be seen of similar
to structural equation modeling
it's not exactly the same
but
having
edges and nodes
is not
the system's mechanics
but given this statistical artifact
it's very easy to say that this causes
that
instead of being proper and saying it's
associated with that
especially because you get into directed
edges
it's like well this is unidirectionally
associated with that through time
it's like come on then just say it
what do you think
yeah
if you ask me I'm I'm digesting it
I need some more time to
get all this a little bit clear but
thanks thanks so much to elaborate on
this question thank you so much yeah
this is like the heart of the textbook
and
the topic
and this is a model architecture it's
not the only model architecture
but
being able to interpret what these model
architectures are
helps us understand a lot about active
inference and then I guess as we are
seeing
it also shines a lot of interesting
light on
broader questions about
scientific modeling
and bigger discussions which I mean to
kind of return to chapter nine
that's
the metabasian perspective
that's why we're centering this
ethological moment
with the modeler's construction
of a cognitive model
whose aboutness is the setup the
experimenter has constructed
and again that
to make That explicit
and encoded in our model structurally is
the innovation
because upon
inquiry I don't think this is a
contentious layout
like if inside of the dashed line
there was a linear regression or an SPM
model
and we said okay we gave we did the
teammates and we had the rat hooked up
to the whatever
optogenetics or to the
um confocal microscope or to the EEG or
to the video camera or to the ultrasound
it's like you got all these scientific
tools okay we set up an experimental
context
and then we observe Behavior
now what is it that was in between
the stimuli and the Observer Behavior
well obviously it was the mouse or the
rat itself
okay so we want to have at the very
least some kind of model of our rats
that is able to perceive experimental
stimuli
and then output Behavior
so we could put a linear regression here
here's temperature on the x-axis and
likelihood of eating cheese on the
y-axis
and we make a regression or we do we we
do model comparison we say okay is it
better compatible with a linear
regression
or a break point regression
or a quadratic regression and so you
have the modeling discussion and they go
okay we use the Bic
and the optimal model to describe the
relationship between temperature and
cheese eating is a break point
regression or it's just a simple linear
regression
would someone turn around and say
why would you say mice are linear
regressions
the obvious response would be
no we just use the linear regression
instrumentally
to describe our data
check out the methods section look again
we followed pretty standard process of
modeling
so that we were able to explain data but
not overfit accuracy minus complexity
and we use standard software tools and
packages so that everybody could
replicate it in its open source
we're definitely not saying that mice
are linear regressions
but when figure 4.3 goes into the box
different questions arise
and I'm not even saying that what what I
have just
um proposed
is infallible
I I think people can have a different
perspective on that
for example they could say Well yeah if
you do linear regression you're not
saying the mouse is a linear regression
but there's something different about
active inference modeling
where when you put figure 4.3 Inside the
Box you've taken on a different set of
commitments
that's a totally valid point to make
if somebody can point to those
commitments
and that's a discussion to have
but simply
considering active inference as like a
software package or an analytics
framework for Behavior
just replace figure 4.3 in your mind's
eye with linear regression
and ask what claims are valid or not
and there are differences between the
models so there may be certain things
that go one way for linear regressions
and another way for pomdps
however
um there's also a broad set of
criticisms that people level at figure
4.3
that are
throwing out the linear regression
as well
but it's a format that people are more
familiar with
I assume this this expands much more
potentially at least
but you could generate a pomdp
with zero explanatory predictive value
and you could have a linear regression
with a good r squared or not
it's not a function of the type of model
selected
in fact the space
of pomdps is just from a parametric
perspective it's much larger
like
here this is still a relatively simple
this is even without showing the
dimensionality of these variables like
if there's 10 affordances B is 10 is
going to have 10 slices
and then if s has um 10
um hidden even there's it's just 10
discrete options
so you're talking about some large
tensors
and parameterizing them from data is
non-trivial
that's what chapter 9 is about and
that's why we have often called for the
development of statistical power
analysis techniques
because even simple models
have many free parameters that might be
related in complex ways
like if C is like within this range
then changes in a do or don't do that
but if a becomes more ambiguous then
this consequence happens over here and
those are those those kinds of like
Rippling effects in the model are not
constrained to which edges are drawn
so we need much better statistical power
analysis techniques
in order to anticipate
the kinds of statistical considerations
that people use for linear regressions
and rna-seq analyzes every day
um but there's nothing about this model
that makes it fit any given data set
better or worse
these are all modelers choice
any closing thoughts or questions on
nine before we scan 10.
I I also think it'll be interesting to
see like
as we have more notebooks and and
accessible software packages that will
help
um
support this deflationary perspective on
active inference
because it'll be like well what what
what part of this um
tiger is the is the B Matrix
and we'll have like a notebook it's like
well now here's the B Matrix in The
Notebook
but it's not in the world
and and then just coming at that Nexus
many many times will be useful but also
I think including people in Empirical
research
is going to help with that
because for one who hasn't read a paper
and or for one who hasn't participated
in empirical behavioral research
with neither of which are bad or good
States just saying some people have
these experiences and some don't
that
um
separation of statistical models from
reality
like mice are not linear regressions
mice are not pomdps
that is definitely
like
a posture
and I don't mean it's a facade
it's a stance
that is
built through
statistical investigation at the very
least reading it if not actually doing
it oneself
like once one sees that there's a
hundred or an open-ended number of ways
to model just the thermometer and the
true temperature of the room
that person will think differently about
map and territory
this is the Final Chapter 10.
in general we are least aware of what
our minds do best
by Dr Minsky
chapter 10 we're going to wrap up active
inference main theoretical points from
the first half of the book chapters one
through five and the Practical
implementations from the second part six
through ten
then we connect the dots abstracting
away from specific models discussed to
focus on integrative aspects
a benefit of active is it provides a
complete solution to the Adaptive
problems that sentient organisms have to
solve this is definitely a sentence that
we've discussed in Prior
cohorts
does it provide a complete solution
or does it
set the table
for a useful
solution or or some other way of of
saying that that you know have the
previous nine chapters
literally resolved all the problems
or have they helped us learn the
Linguistics and techniques that help us
frame the problems so that we can come
to heuristic Solutions but again these
are the kinds of things we can discuss
um 10.2 wrapping up
this part all textbook offers a
systematic account of the theoretical
underpinnings part one practical
implementations of active inference part
two
they review chapter one chapter two
long low road
chapter 3 High Road
you need your Gym gear tomorrow
chapter five
highlights some of the applications and
research in active inference in the
mammalian nervous system
chapter 6 the recipe to design active
inference models
chapter 7 and 8 discrete and continuous
time generative models in active
inference
chapter 9
active inference in the context of
model-based data analysis
connecting the dots
integrative perspectives on octave
inference Daniel Dennett and the whole
iguana
hey instead of going deep down the
rabbit hole with the prospective working
memory module subsystem
and then developing this whole just so
story backwards from that how about
modeling a complete cognitive creature
and environmental Niche for it to cope
with
they talk about that whole iguana
perspective
and the way that diverse cognitive
phenomena attention memory anticipation
etc etc
can be understood of using this active
inference first principles framework
active inference doesn't start by
assembling separate predefined
cognitive functions perception decision
making and planning
rather it starts by providing a complete
solution or approach
to derive implications about cognitive
functions
that helps us identify
patterns of cognitive phenomena
for example optimal foraging in
different settings
finally
active inference offers a principled
means of understanding corresponding
neural computations
it speaks to multiple levels of Mars
hierarchy Mars levels
and very briefly we'll discuss more in
the coming weeks
implications for psychological function
as if we were sketching or prompting a
psychology textbook
predictive brains minds and processing
what does active inference have to do
and how does it build within the lineage
of research on the predictive brain
predictive mind
perception and different psychological
and philosophical lineages for example
going back to helmholtz and before
on perception
Bayesian brain
action
idea motor
Theory
cybernetics
optimal control theory
utility in decision making
Bayesian decision Theory
reinforcement learning
planning as inference
behavior and bounded rationality
free energy theory of bounded
rationality
valence emotion and motivation
homeostasis allostasis and terraceptor
processing
attention salience and epistemic
Dynamics
role learning causal inference and
fashionalization
active inference and other fields open
directions
social cultural Dynamics machine
learning and Robotics
and summary with the Lord of the Rings
quote
ultimately we are confident that you
will continue to pursue active inference
in some form
okay
thanks for the chapter 9 discussion
we will come back for the coming two
weeks in chapter 10 and then one final
session so thank you all